houstonfoodbank.org 2019-05-26

# The Houston Food Bank Web Site Privacy Policy

                                  The Houston Food Bank
                                  Web Site Privacy Policy
Your right to privacy is very important to us. We recognize that providing us with personal
information is an act of trust. Therefore, we have created a privacy policy to protect your personal
information.
Questions regarding this statement should be directed to The Houston Food Bank by sending an
e-mail message to cferrell@houstonfoodbank.org. Please reference this privacy policy in your
subject line.
Your Personal Information
Personal Information Collected
In general, when you visit our web site and access information you remain anonymous. We do
not require you to register or provide personal information to us to view our web site. You do
have an option to join our mailing list on the web site, or to make a financial contribution and in
both cases we collect contact information and if a contribution is involved, credit card information.
Similarly, we collect information on individuals who may volunteer services or attend events.
What Information We Collect and How We Use That Information
Our mailing list form requires users to give us contact information that may include name, e-mail
address, format preference (HTML vs. plain text), physical address, interests, and similar
information. We do not request or store sensitive information from our visitors, such as social
security numbers. The credit card transaction available through our web site is handled by a
secure, encrypted process provided by a third party processor under contract to The Houston
Food Bank.
Use of Your Personal Information
On a selective basis, personally identifiable information is used internally to identify recipients for
written and e-mail communications designed to inform individuals of organizational updates,
events, food drives, and campaigns for financial support. You have the right to opt-out of
these mailings, and can do so by notifying The Houston Food Bank in writing of this preference.
The Houston Food Bank never shares your personal information with outside organizations.
Internet Protocol Address
An Internet Protocol (IP) address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer
when you use the Internet. We collect an IP address from all visitors to our web site. We use IP
addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our web site, analyze usage
trends, track users' interactions with the web site, gather broad demographic information for
aggregate use in order for us to improve the web site, and deliver customized, personalized
content. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.
Links to Third-Party Web Sites
We sometimes provide links to third party web sites existing outside of The Houston Food Bank.
Since we do not control the content or functionality of these web sites, we encourage you to
review the privacy policies posted on these third-party web sites. Any link from
http://houstonfoodbank.org to such a third-party web site does not denote an affiliation with the
web site or an endorsement of its viewpoint(s) or mission(s).

Security of Your Information
Security
All sensitive information (such as your credit card information) provided to The Houston Food
Bank is transmitted using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system
that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. We also
protect account information by placing it on a secure portion of our web site that is only
accessible by certain qualified employees of The Houston Food Bank.
Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can ever be 100% secure. While we strive
to protect your information to the fullest extent, we cannot ensure or completely guarantee the
security of such information.
Your Credit Card Information
When you enter your credit card information into a form field on http://houstonfoodbank.org , your
credit card information is encrypted and transmitted securely to The Houston Food Bank or to our
third party processor. Neither The Houston Food Bank nor our third party processor store your
credit card information on a permanent basis; your credit card information is only used for the
duration of the transaction and is then deleted from our records.
We take the utmost precaution to keep your credit card information safe and secure. If you are
uncomfortable submitting your credit card information online, you can also contribute to The
Houston Food Bank by printing out the online form and mailing it to:
Attn: Development
The Houston Food Bank
535 Portwall St.
Houston, TX 77029
You can also call our Development Office at 713-223-3700 to authorize a credit card transaction.
Cookies
What are "Cookies"?
Cookies are small files sent from a web server to your computer through your browser program.
A non-persistent cookie enables a web site to temporarily keep information on your computer as
you travel from one page to another on our web site. This cookie is automatically deleted from
your machine when you close your browser. Because these cookies are necessary to provide
some functions, failure to allow such cookies may make some of the functions on our web site
unavailable to you.
Our Use of Cookies
The Houston Food Bank uses cookies for various reasons. We only read information from the
specific cookies that are written by our web sites. Cookies may be used to store some history
about the parts of our web site that you visited to help you navigate our web sites more easily or
to alert you to related pages on our web site that may interest you.
Rev: 5/10/13
